## **ALBERTUS ANDITO**

+44 748 254 8897 · +62 813 9470 5836

albertus.andito@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/albertus-andito · albertus-andito.com

Final year Computer Science student with a year of experience in industry as a software engineer. Interested in machine learning and natural language processing, as well as their applications in real-life problems. Proven skills in building and maintaining systems. Always embrace rapid changes of technology and not afraid to learn something new to solve problems and innovate.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **SEP 2017 – JUN 2021**

## BSc (Hons) Computer Science (with an industrial placement year), University of Sussex

Currently doing my Final Year Project on "Using Dynamic Knowledge Graph for Fake News Detection". I am building a system where an existing knowledge base can be extended with semantic triples extracted from trusted news articles. The fake news detection will be done by comparing the to-be-verified facts from the news with the knowledge base.

Overall second year result: 84%

Relevant Modules: Compilers and Computer Architecture (90%) ● Databases (92%) ● Natural Language Engineering (89%) ● Computer Networks (92%) ● Fundamentals of Machine Learning (71%) ● Software Engineering (85%) ● Human-Computer Interaction ● Introduction to Computer Security

#### **JULY 2014 - MAY 2017**

## Mathematics & Sciences, SMA Asisi (Asisi Senior High School), Jakarta, Indonesia

Head of Student Council (2016 period). Finalist in National Young Inventors Award competition. Graduated with the highest graduating grade in my cohort.

## **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

## **OCT 2020 - PRESENT**

## Data and Digital Technology Staff, PPI United Kingdom

- A voluntary position with the Indonesian Student Association in the UK.
- Main project: developed a database portal of all Indonesian student profiles in the UK, which can be accessed by the students. Focused on the backend and authorization development.
- Technologies used: NodeJS, Express REST API, MongoDB, OAuth2.

#### OCT 2020 - PRESENT

## Student Demonstrator, University of Sussex

 Assisting tutor on first year module Introduction to Programming lab sessions by helping students and answering student queries with Java programming.

## **JUL 2019 - SEP 2020**

## Software Engineer Intern, Oracle, Reading

- 1-year internship with Adaptive Intelligence Applications framework team, which is responsible for building a machine learning framework to be used by Oracle's applications.
- Spent first half of internship helping internal customers to use our machine learning framework (e.g., by writing code examples). Also created an automated end-to-end testing for our service.
- For the second half of the internship, I joined the team that develops the framework components, using Kanban agile methodology. Involved in implementing new features, as well as maintaining the framework.
- Expanded my ability to write high-quality and clean production code using design patterns.
- Main technologies used: Java, Docker, Kubernetes, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure, Git

#### **JUL 2018 - AUG 2018**

## Tech Intern, OLX Indonesia, Jakarta

- Created desktop application using Electron and ReactJS used by the finance department to compare payment transactions data in two Excel files with different structures.
- Developed OLX PWA (Progressive Web App) by using React-Redux, React-Loadable, and service worker.

#### **VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE**

#### **AUGUST 2019 - OCTOBER 2019**

## Instructor, Oracle's Kids Who Code

I taught basics of coding to kids aged 10 using simplified Java language as part of Oracle UK programme.

#### **SEP 2017 - MAY 2018**

## Poster Designer, Building Futures (ISC Sussex)

I was responsible for designing posters promoting our charity events.

## **SKILLS**

Java Python JavaScript React JS

- SQL
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- HelmGit
- Bash

- Object-oriented programming
- Agile software development
- Natural language processing
- Machine learning
- Cloud computing

## **HONORS & AWARDS**

## **Above and Beyond Award**

## JUN 2020, Oracle

An award for intern that has exceptionally exceeded expectations throughout the placement. Out of 49 interns, there were 6 interns that received awards, including this award.

## **Certificate of Outstanding Academic Achievement**

## JAN 2018, University of Sussex International Study Centre

This certificate was given by the STEM department of University of Sussex International Study Centre for my outstanding academic achievement across all modules in Semester 1.

# Certificate of Merit as a Finalist of the 9th National Young Inventors Award (NYIA) 2016 SEP 2016, Indonesian Institute of Sciences (LIPI)

The certificate was given for my invention, Refrigerator Wings Hanger (Hanger Sayap Kulkas), which now has a copyright issued to it.

## **ORGANISATION**

## Persatuan Pelajar Indonesia Brighton (Indonesian Student Association in Brighton) SEP 2017 – PRESENT

## **University of Sussex Indonesian Society**

#### DEC 2018 - JUNE 2019, President

I initiated the creation of Indonesian Society in my university. Our goal is to promote Indonesian culture throughout the campus.

## **TEST SCORE**

## **IELTS (International English Language Testing System)**

**APR 2016,** 7.0